# **ANDREW FRITZ**

196 Stockholm St., Apt. 1L Brooklyn, NY 11237 512-771-2153 atf245@nyu.edu

#### **PROFILE**

Junior/entry full-stack developer. Former physics major that took many programming, math, and science courses as an undergrad. Experience with modern front-end and back-end development. Strong math skills and logical thinking. In a past career worked 3 years as a patent attorney representing a variety of high tech companies.

Portfolio Page: atf1206.github.io

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Java, and C++

**Additional Web Tools:** HTML, CSS, jQuery, Node.js, Git, MySQL, XML, JSON, etc. **Developer Coursework:** 500 hour front-end development course @ freecodecamp.com.

**Other relevant Coursework:** Full college math sequence including Differential Equations, Linear Algebra, Probability, and Statistics, Elements of Computer Programming [Java], Scientific Computation, and Computational Economics.

#### **EDUCATION**

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF LAW, New York, NY

J.D., May 2012

### UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN, Austin, TX

B.A. Physics and Plan II (Liberal Arts Honors program), May 2006

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## TIAJOLOFF & KELLY, LLP, New York, NY

Associate, September 2012 - September 2015

Drafted and prosecuted patent applications in the areas of electrical engineering (e.g. microwave circuits), physics (e.g. satellite dishes, software artificial physics systems), mechanical engineering (e.g. solar tracking panels), materials science (e.g. quartz glass, chemical deposition), and others at Midtown law firm.

### THE GRIFFIN SCHOOL, Austin, TX

Teacher, 2008-2009

Taught high school physics and math classes to all levels of high school students. Prepared and taught SAT courses. Provided tutoring in math and science and operated summer math and science programs.

#### THE PRINCETON REVIEW, Austin, TX

Instructor, 2005-2008

Taught GMAT courses to prospective MBA candidates, GRE to Graduate School applicants, and MCAT physics to prospective medical students.

### **OTHER**

Also speak Italian (Near Fluent) and Spanish (Conversational). 1500/1600 SAT score (high school). Lifelong soccer player and amateur drummer.